Hi,
everyone.
I wonder if you've noticed
how badly the US dollar has plummeted this year.
The first half of the year
was its worst in nearly half a century
From the beginning of the year to now,
the US dollar index has fallen by over 10%.
Don't think 10% isn't a big deal.
This is the US dollar
not Bitcoin.
It's the benchmark for global assets.
This benchmark has shrunk by 10% in six months,
roughly equivalent to everyone growing 10% taller.
At the same time,
global asset prices have seen a long-awaited surge,
with gold being the most dramatic.
Just look at this chart.
This shows gold's performance over the past half century.
I can only describe it as crazy.
Bitcoin has also hit new highs, which is
also crazy
but it has always be crazy.
Also,
global stock markets are also rising
U.S. stocks, European stocks, A-shares, Hong Kong stocks, and Japanese stocks
are all up .
Something unusual must be going on
What is the unusual part?
Let's take a look at
the reasons behind the dollar's plunge.
Today,
I'm going to talk with you in a more professional
but at the same time intuitive, and interesting way
We talk with charts.
Let's look at a few charts.
This is the US dollar index
and this is the S&P 500 index.
You see,
the stock market and the dollar were highly correlated before
rising and falling together.
Look at these two
holding hands, happily resonating.
But how come in May,
just when the stock market was halfway through its recovery,
stock market say
"Forget it, I don't want to play with you anymore,"
and ran away
The US dollar was left alone at the bottom.
Let me show you another resonance that is even happier.
This is the resonance between
US dollar index and the US 10-year Treasury bond rate.
They were playing well together before
but they broke up in May.
What's more important is the next chart.
This is the S&P 500 index of US stocks.
This is a mysterious index .
The correlation between the two in the past five years
has been as high as an astonishing 82.4%.
So why did all these happen?
How does it relate to the US dollar's plunge this year?
After watching the end of the video today,
you will understand.
The first force driving the US dollar down,
and also the biggest force this year,
is risk.
In fact,
risk has always been a good friend of the US dollar.
Most of the time, the US dollar is a safe-haven asset.
You can see that the US dollar has ushered in a wave of gains
since September last year.
Why?
On the one hand, the US economy
was indeed relatively strong
but another key factor was global risk aversion,
especially when everyone saw that Trump was about to be elected
and who knew how he would mess with other countries.
Investors thought
don't make blind guesses,
holding US dollars will never be wrong, right?
However, as soon as Trump came to power this year, the intensity of
his series of tariff policies
far exceeded everyone's expectations.
At this time, the market reacted.
Wow, I bought the US dollar to avoid risks
but the US dollar is the biggest risk.
This triggers the US Dollar
free falling twice in the first half of this year
See this is the US stock VIX
which is also the panic index.
When people panic,
the US dollar falls.
The two major plunges of the US dollar
were all caused by Trump's tariff-related policies.
So this year, you can see that in April,
it was basically the market's
concern about the risk of a tariff war or instead the risk of Trump
And it got even weirder after that.
We just saw that the interest rate of 10-year US Treasury bonds
began to break up with the US dollar in May.
Why?
It's because the market is worried about different risks.
We have done some videos before to talk about Trump and
his plans.
Miran, the chairman of his Council of Economic Advisers,
specially issued a "Guideline"
with many radical and
contradictory proposals
He also imagined the
Mar-a-Lago agreement.
Later, in fact,
the series of policies introduced by Trump
were surprisingly similar to this "Guideline".
Sure enough, he introduced an extremely tough tariff policy
and tried to interfere with the Federal Reserve's policy.
As expected, the One Big Beautiful Bill Act was approved.
everyone's concerns
are no longer about short-term tariff risks
but longer-term issues.
If things continue like this,
can the U.S. Treasury debt be curbed?
Can the U.S. government repay its debts?
Will U.S. inflation get out of control?
What does this indicate?
It indicates that the market
is starting to worry about the U.S. government's credit risk
and is selling off long-term U.S. Treasury bonds,
causing long-term interest rates to rise.
This is why we have this chart.
After May,
the U.S. dollar and long-term Treasury bond rates "broke up."
Why were they in resonance before?
Let me explain.
If the long-term interest rate of the U.S. dollar rises,
it means the return on investing in the dollar will increase,
incentivising people to buy dollars ,
causing the dollar to rise.
So, they used to walk hand in hand.
But this time,
although the return rate has increased,
the risk has also increased,
so people are less willing to buy,
resulting in rising long-term interest rates
and a falling dollar.
The two broke up.
I don't know if you're confused,
but in short, they broke up
because the credit risk of the U.S. government has increased.
It's like
a couple
who used to be happy and sad together,
mainly due to external factors.
But now, one of them
starts to act up,
causing a crisis of trust between the two
They broke up,
So here comes the question again.
Given that the risk of the US dollar is so great and
the credit risk of US Treasury bonds has become higher,
so why is the US stock market still soaring?
Why did the US stock market and the US dollar "break up" again?
You see,
although everyone thinks that the US dollar is very risky
and the US government bonds
are not as reliable as before
but US stocks
and US companies are still very attractive.
US stocks have indeed continued to rise for many years.
So even though people don't trust the US government and
the US dollar so much
they will still buy US stocks.
This has led to the continuous rise of US stocks,
especially AI-related stocks.
In the past, there were stocks like Nvidia, Microsoft, Google, and Meta, and
recently there has been something like Oracle.
It briefly created a new richest man in the world,
but was later surpassed by Musk.
We can talk about Oracle later if we have the chance.
In short,
valuations of AI-related stocks are already quite exaggerated.
So why do foreign capital poured in to invest in US stocks?
Why is the US dollar not rising but falling?
The answer behind this is:
hedging.
Because the foreign capital that has recently entered
has begun to hedge the US dollar risk.
What is hedging the US dollar risk?
For example
I am a foreign investor
and I have a fund of RMB 1 billion.
Then I want to buy Nvidia
, for example
I need to convert these RMB into US dollars
before buying Nvidia.
In this way,
I will also bear the foreign exchange risk of the US dollar
and the stock price risk of Nvidia
but now I don't want to bear
the foreign exchange risk of more than 100 million US dollars,
I just want to buy Nvidia.
What should I do?
I can hedge
That way, I can short over 100 million US dollars
in the forex futures, forwards, or swap markets
while going long on
1 billion RMB
In this way, I have hedged the foreign exchange risk.
The demand for the US dollar has not increased.
Hey, there is no evidence to support
Let's look at the chart today.
You see, this is
the proportion of hedged and unhedged funds
flowing into US stock ETFs in the past three years.
You can clearly see that
more than 80% of overseas funds
flowing into US stocks
did not hedge the US dollar risk
because the US dollar itself is also an investment product,
and most of the time it was still quite strong
but this year it took a 180-degree turn,
with more than 80% of funds starting to hedge.
In fact, the resonance between the US dollar and the US stock market
was not difficult to understand.
You see, many people who buy US dollars
will invest in US stocks.
If you want to buy US stocks ,
you have to exchange them for US dollars first,
so the correlation between the two is very high.
This time, everyone is buying US stocks,
but hedging the US dollar risk
and not buying US dollars.
This is what led to this chart.
After April,
the US dollar and the US stock market "broke up"
just like the couple just now who
had a trust crisis and broke up,
but
I still like your piano very much,
so even though we broke up
I can still go to your house often to play the piano
without any interruption.
I know today's analogy may not be so appropriate,
Just take it as some light entertainment, guys
On the one hand ,
people will flee from the US dollar
and turn to buy other assets.
On the other hand,
the depreciation of the US dollar
will also drive up the prices of other assets
from a valuation perspective
This has, to a certain extent, driven
up the prices of almost all other assets except the US dollar.
The most typical example here is gold.
Think about it,
the main theme of the financial market this year is risk aversion.
In the past, risk aversion mainly involved fleeing to US dollar assets
and Japanese yen assets.
But now the
US dollar is not doing well,
and the Japanese yen is also very volatile
We will talk about this in the year-end summary.
Therefore, the safe-haven assets
are either the Swiss Franc
or gold.
But the Swiss franc
is very limited after all
so gold
has become the first choice for many people in this chaotic world
Let's again look at the chart.
This shows the flow of
gold ETFs in different regions this year.
It's obvious that there's been a huge influx of funds this year
and surprisingly,
the largest influx of funds this year has come from North America.
You should know that in the past, the main demand for gold
actually came from Asia,
but this year,
North America and Europe are also constantly buying.
But what's interesting is that
because the price of gold has risen so much,
it's a bit expensive to make jewelry,
so the demand for jewelry has begun to decline this year.
As a result, the total demand for gold
has not changed much
but the price has continued to rise.
Well, we just said that
the number one driving force behind the plunge in the US dollar this year is risk
or more so: Trump
So what is the second biggest driving force?
You see, in recent months,
long-term interest rates and US stocks have been out of sync,
so who's driving the dollar's trend?
And who's the dollar dating?
Look at the chart.
This is the recent trend of the US dollar index
and this is
the price of the federal funds rate futures
expiring in December.
Something just doesn’t quite add up, does it?
Let me give it a turn
This is the new target for the dollar.
Don't be confused.
This is actually the market's expectation of the December interest rate level.
If you don't know what it means,
you can check out our first futures video
To put it bluntly,
the recent trend of the dollar
is driven by market expectations of a Fed rate cut.
That is, I expect the US dollar index to follow the
changes in the interest rate at the end of the year.
You see, in the first half of the year, the dollar's trend was driven
by Trump
while in the second half
... Powell
We already looked into this when Powell made his first rate cut
last year.
The core of his decision to cut interest rates
is his dual mandate
inflation and employment
In theory, he hopes to suppress inflation to below 2%
or even lower
before starting to cut rates
During this year
some core indicators,
whether CPI
or core PCE,
have basically been hovering around 3%.
Although it is not the most ideal state
it is acceptable.
Therefore, the Fed's main decision-making focus
is on employment data.
In other words,
he wants to see weaker employment data
before cutting rates
The Fed's control of monetary policy
is like
a class teacher
who has to manage a class of students.
He has two KPIs
he wants students to have good grades
and to keep their bodies healthy
the class teacher
can only control one thing
which is the amount of homework.
This is like the Fed can only control interest rates
If more homework is given,
the grades may go up,
but the body cannot handle
If less homework is given,
the grades may go down,
but the body may recover a little
becomes better.
I'm just giving an analogy,
please don't take it too seriously.
Look,
the situation faced by
the Fed and the head teacher
is actually a bit like
the goals of inflation and employment.
Often, it really is a case of one falling as the other rises.
In the past one or two years,
the grades of these students are pretty good.
Although they cannot be said to be excellent
they all score more than 80 points.
The head teacher has recently paid special attention
to their physical health.
If I find
everyone's health shows signs of decline,
I'll start reducing the amount of homework.
But if I don't see
any health decline,
and everyone is healthy and
doing well academically
I can't reduce the amount of homework.
Otherwise, everyone might be too energetic
and go out to play
and if they play too much, they might even damage their health.
Then their academic performance will be bad
and that's even worse .
This is economic "stagflation."
Students might also be in stagnation
a clever pun for everyone.
Anyway, that's what I mean .
The class teacher
keeps an eye on the students' health indicators every month,
and the Fed keeps an eye on the employment data every month
When the data gets bad enough,
immediately cut interest rates.
What's the actual situation?
In the first half of this year, it was average, but also OK.
In addition, Trump's policies
has very high uncertainty
so the Fed cut interest rates until halfway.
And in recent months,
you can see that this is the expected interest rate in December.
There have been big jumps at the beginning of the month for these three months
This is actually due to
the market reaction after the release of
the NFP non-farm payroll data.
The July employment data was not bad.
Everyone thought that the Fed might not cut the rates much
so the interest rate jumped up.
The August employment data was very bad.
You can see that the interest rate
dropped suddenly
This data is very critical
because it is really too bad.
It seems that the students in my class
have started to feel dizzy
and vomit.
The class teacher has to immediately reduce the amount of homework.
So in August, after that data,
the market was almost certain
the Fed would cut interest rates in September.
Then, the September data wasn't very good,
and interest rates fell further.
And the US dollar index
basically fluctuated along with
the interest rate
So, the market had already fully anticipated
the Fed's rate cut.
When the Fed actually cut,
the market reaction wasn't exactly minimal,
but rather unremarkable.
I actually want to discuss
the NFP non-farm payroll data.
There's something very interesting
and even a bit strange about it lately
It's so inaccurate.
I don't know if you've seen similar news before,
but the recent revisions are truly exaggerated.
This data is called NFP
Non-Farm Payroll.
In simple terms,
it tells us how much employment grew each month
excluding sectors like agriculture,
self-employment, and so on.
For example, if the survey results show 100,000 in one month,
this means that
the non-farm payroll population in the US
increased by 100,000 in that month .
In theory,
if the Fed wants to see the employment situation more accurately,
it must be the unemployment rate.
However, the problem with the unemployment rate is
that it fluctuates too little from month to month and
is not sensitive enough.
Moreover, it also depends on the participation rate
that is, how many people want to find a job,
which is obviously very subjective
and more difficult to judge.
Non-farm payroll data
is just a number,
which is relatively more objective
and much easier to measure.
It's like
a class teacher wants to understand everyone's health status.
In theory, you should have a physical examination
and a psychological assessment monthly.
But if you have to take the test every month,
it is obviously too expensive,
so I can settle for the second best
and simply look at average sleep time of each student.
Although it isn't the best indicator
but it can be used to roughly
track everyone's health.
I might then do a full physical at the end of the year.
The non-farm payroll data
is a bit like the class teacher
checking sleep time.
But what's so outrageous about it?
The NFP, which seems to be the most accurate,
has seen significant revisions
for several consecutive months.
For example, the May employment data
was released on June 6th, showing an increase of 139,000
which was OK.
Then it was revised on July 3rd to 144,000,
5,000 more than the original.
The market felt that it was better, but
then it was revised again on August 1st.
Sorry,
I was careless.
I was wrong for the past two months.
It was not 144,000
but 19,000.
The June employment data was also similar.
The first release said it was 147,000
and then it was revised on August 1st to say, "
Sorry,
it's not 147,000."
It was 14,000,
and then the next month, again
Sorry,
it didn't increase by 14,000
but decreased by 13,000.
Don't you think this revision is outrageous?
I even suspect
that there was a decimal point mistake
That's why we saw the market plummet
on August 1st
because it suffered a triple blow that day.
Not only was the newly released
July data worse than expected,
the June data was revised down by more than 130,000,
and the May data was revised down by more than 120,000.
So a few hours after this number came out,
Trump was furious.
He said, "Your Census Bureau is deliberately embarrassing me
and you are manipulating the data."
He immediately fired the director of the Bureau of Labor Statistics.
How could this data
be so inaccurate?
The point is that it is such an important data.
The most important interest rate in the world
depends on U.S. employment.
U.S. employment depends on this  number
It determines
the trend of the global capital market.
And then every month
my guess is probably more accurate than this
so many people may have conspiracy theories about
whether this data is manipulated.
I don't know about this
but I can explain
some possible reasons
why there is such a large correction in theory.
This part may be more theoretical.
If you are not interested,
you can skip to this part.
First of all, the volume of this correction
is not as large as everyone feels,
because this number is a variable.
The total non-farm payroll population in the United States
is about 159.5 million.
Your increase of 100,000
is actually equivalent to 0.06%.
In fact, corrections of more than 100,000
are common in history
Why does it feel so obvious recently?
Because the data was relatively good before.
For example, if there is an increase of 300,000 jobs per month,
then if you reduce it by 100,000, it will become 200,000,
a decrease of 1/3. Although it is not a small amount
but it is acceptable.
But recently,
it has increased by 110,000.
Then you lowered it by 100,000 to 10,000.
It is also a reduction of 100,000.
but you have lowered it by 90%.
Psychologically,
you feel that it has been adjusted a lot.
This is one of the reasons.
However,
the extent of its revision has increased significantly recently,
and it is indeed more inaccurate.
This requires us to talk about the non-farm payroll data.
How is it calculated ?
It mainly relies on questionnaires
They ask 120,000 companies
how many employees they have in the past month.
What is the problem?
After the pandemic,
companies have been submitting questionnaires more and more slowly.
It is actually impossible to submit
all 120,000 company questionnaires immediately in the same month.
Therefore, generally, in
the first month, a data is announced based on
the number of questionnaires already received.
In the next two months,
as the questionnaires are collected little by little,
the data will be revised.
You see, this is the historical
recovery rate of questionnaires in three months.
In the first month,
before the pandemic, 70 to 80% could be recovered.
After the pandemic, it is now less than 60%.
Therefore,
the accuracy of the number obtained in the first month
will be significantly reduced.
Moreover, even if
all 120,000 questionnaires are collected,
It's just a sample.
A comprehensive survey must be conducted every year
and then the annual data must be revised.
In September they just completed
annual non-farm employment data
from April 2024 to March 2025
The data for the entire year was actually revised down by 910,000
which is the largest downward revision in history.
The official explanation is
some model adjustment or something.
Some people have conspiracy theories.
Some people say it's an immigration issue.
I won't analyse it here
I dont know it.
But what's interesting is that
this time the annual data was revised so much, but
Trump didn't get angry
Why is that?
Because the data that was revised down this time
were mainly during Biden's term.
It has nothing to do with me.
It's not my fault, right?
It only shows that the economic performance during Biden's term
was truly dismal
We just talked about
how the dollar fared with Trump in the first half of the year
and Powell in the second.
But things haven't been going so well
for Trump and Powell lately
This is actually
a major force influencing the dollar
the independence of the Federal Reserve.
We previously did an episode
specifically discussing Fed Chairman Powell
Trump constantly berated and teased him,
even threatening to fire him at one point
because he wanted the Fed to cut interest rates quickly,
but the Fed wouldn't listen.
Let me tell you,
Trump really does have some tricks up his sleeve.
Seeing that Powell seemed inconvenient to touch,
he targeted another member of the Federal Reserve Board
Lisa Cook
Trump announced in August
that he would fire Cook from her position as a Fed governor.
This wasn't a threat at all.
I want to fire her,
I want to dismiss her
Found a reason like
false housing and mortgage information
or some other nonsense.
Bust as mentioned before
The Fed is basically the rock that holds up
global confidence in the dollar
In the past 20 years,
it has become increasingly independent of the US government.
But Trump obviously doesn't believe this
I don't know if I have the right,
but I can make an announcement first.
Hey, this is very Trump.
Later in September
as expected, the court ruled that Trump
did not have sufficient grounds to fire Cook,
and the move was blocked.
The market was really scared.
If Trump
really can fire Federal Reserve governors at will,
then the Fed will basically
be named Trump
But I tell you,
Trump's actions are not over yet.
In August this year
there was another director announced his resignation in a very bizarre way,
immediately after, Trump quite naturally
placed one of his close allies into
the Federal Reserve Board.
Do you know who it is?
It's Miran, the one who helped him
plan the economic blueprint
and the Mar-a-Lago agreement.
We've talked about this before
hahaha,
I feel like "we've talked about this before"
I seem to have said it many times today.
I don't know if it's a coincidence or what.
You see, I only make a few videos a year, but
all of them linked up today.
We talked about interest rate cuts
Trump's economic plan,
and the struggle between Trump and the Federal Reserve.
It's like a TV series,
You can watch it all together.
Let's get back to the topic.
After Trump arranged for Miran to join the board,
Miran fulfilled his promise
He was the only one who dissented from
the Fed's 25 basis point rate cut
believing it should be 50 basis points.
And then
The Fed usually publishes what's called a 'dot plot'
showing
each board member's expectations for future interest rates.
Although the dot plot is anonymous,
look at the result:
one dot
seems out of place.
Everyone else thinks the year-end rate should be 3.6% or higher,
but thsi dot
he
thinks it should plummet to below 3%.
Who is he?
Who do you think he is?
Miran went from an unknown figure
to the centre of global attention in just one year
even joining the Federal Reserve Board.
Guess it pays to follow the right boss
that promotion came real quick.
But they're a bit too deliberate and obvious.
The way he behaves
is a bit unsightly.
Anyway, whether it is trying to fire Cook
or stuffing Miran into the Fed
it shows that Trump
is actually trying his best
to interfere with the Fed's interest rate decision.
This has also made the market very worried.
In fact, it is also a very important reason for
the weakness of the US dollar.
Well, what will happen next?
Will the US dollar continue to weaken?
Let's look at it from the perspective of interest rates.
In Europe
the interest rate is almost done dropping
and Japan is about to start raising interest rates.
So from the perspective of relative interest rate differentials,
the US dollar in the interest rate cut cycle
will continue to weaken.
Morgan Stanley also predicts that
the US dollar
may depreciate further by about 10% to
around 91 by the end of next year .
Alright, what does a weaker dollar
mean for other countries?
In short, one word
Great
In two words
Incredibly great.
I was being a little playful just now.
but it's true that during the dollar’s rate cuts
liquidity flows
capital flows to other countries around the world,
things will generally be better for other countries.
This is especially evident in developing countries.
You see, in early 2000s
the US dollar interest rate cuts
directly drove the global economic boom in those years
even leading to economic overheating and
triggering the 2008 financial tsunami .
Before that, the large interest rate cuts in the 1990s
drove capital inflows into emerging economies around the world
even causing overheating,
leading to the financial crises in Mexico, Asia, and Russia.
So, the US dollar's interest rate cut cycle
will heat up other economies
and even cause them to overheat.
Of course, the examples I cited are relatively extreme,
with interest rate cuts of more than 500 basis points
This time,
the market predicts another 100 basis point cut
to 3%, that's about it
definitely incomparable to the previous ones.
It's just a very mild, small-scale rate cut.
In short,
the Fed's rate cut and
the weakening of the US dollar
will be slightly beneficial to other countries
especially developing countries.
In fact, it is also good for China.
Although China is also cutting interest rates
but the US rate cut
will make the People's Bank of China feel more comfortable cutting rates.
There is no need to worry too much
about whether the RMB will continue to fall.
Okay, we have looked at so many charts today
and know why US stocks and US bonds
"broke up" with the US dollar.
You can tell me whether our chart-based analysis
is objective and intuitive.
What is the last and most crucial chart?
Which mysterious index
so highly correlated with the S&P 500?
The answer is
Lin's number of fans.
What does this indicate?
It shows what is really driving the rise of US stocks
Are you guys
I'm just kidding
What it actually shows is that data
can sometimes be deceiving .
A high correlation
could just be a coincidence.
What do you think?
That added some serious depth, right?